[
  {
    "_id": "aDfdf",
    "cat": "Dua's Importance",
    "subCat": [
      {
        "_id": "1a",
        "section": "The servant is dependent on his Lord",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "The servant is dependent on his Lord#1",
            "answer": "All human beings depend on Allah for their welfare and prevention of evil in various matters of their religion and world. Allah says (interpretation of the meaning): O mankind, you are those in need of Allah, while Allah is the Free of need, the Praiseworthy.",
            "arabic": "",
            "transliteration": "",
            "translation": "",
            "reference": "Surah Al-Fatir 35:15"
          },
          {
            "question": "The servant is dependent on his Lord#2",
            "answer": "Prophet (ﷺ) used to say after every compulsory prayer, The servant will ask his Lord for all of his religiously and worldly needs, because the treasure of all things is in the hands of Allah. Allah says (interpretation of the meaning): “And there is not a thing but that with Us are its depositories, and We do not send it down except according to a known measure.” (Sura Al-Hijr 15:21) No one can withhold what Allah gives; And, no one can give what he resists.",
            "arabic": "لَا إِلَهَ إِلَّا اللَّهُ وَحْدَهُ لَا شَرِيْكَ لَهُ، لَهُ الْمُلْكُ وَلَهُ الْحَمْدُ وَهُوَ عَلَى كُلِّ شَيْءٍ قَدِيرٌ، اَللَّهُمَّ لَا مَانِعَ لِمَا أَعْطَيْتَ وَلَا مُعْطِيَ لِمَا مَنَعْتَ وَلَا يَنْفَعُ ذَا الْجَدِّ مِنْكَ الْجَدُّ",
            "transliteration": "Laa ilaaha illallahu wahdahu laa sharika lahu, lahul-mulku wa lahul-hamdu wa huwa 'alaa kulli shay'in qadir. Allaahumma laa maani'a limaa a'taita wa laa mu'tia limaa mana'ta wa laa yanfa'u dhal-jaddi minka al-jaddu",
            "translation": "There is none worthy of worship except Allah alone with no partner or associate. He is the Dominion and to Him be all praise, and He is able to do all things. O Allah, one can withhold what You have given and none can give what You have withheld, and no wealth or fortune can benefit anyone for from You comes all wealth and fortune.",
            "reference": "Bukhari: 844"
          },
          {
            "question": "The reward of freeing of a slave",
            "answer": "The Prophet (ﷺ) said: The person who says the above statement 10 times It would be as if he had freed four of Ishmael's (As) children from slavery.",
            "arabic": "لَا إِلَهَ إِلَّا اللَّهُ وَحْدَهُ لَا شَرِيكَ لَهُ، لَهُ الْمُلْكُ، وَلَهُ الْحَمْدُ، وَهُوَ عَلَى كُلِّ شَيْءٍ قَدِيرٌ",
            "transliteration": "Laa ilahaa illAllahu wahdahu laa sharika lahu, lahul-mulku wa lahul-hamdu wa huwa 'alaa kulli shay'in qadir",
            "translation": "None has the right to be worshipped but Allah alone, Who has no partner. His is the dominion and His is the praise, and He is Able to do all things.",
            "reference": "Bukhari: 6404"
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "_id": "1b",
        "section": "The most important thing to ask Allah for",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "Allah's guidance #1",
            "answer": "He whom Allah guides is the [rightly] guided, but he whom He leaves astray - never will you find for him a protecting guide. (Surah Al-Kahf 18:17)",
            "reference": "Surah Al-Fatihah 1:5"
          },
          {
            "question": "Allah's guidance #2",
            "answer": "Guide me through that which there has been difference concerning the truth, verily, You are upon a straight path.",
            "reference": "Muslim: 770"
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "_id": "1c",
        "section": "Ask for paradise & protection from fire",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "Ask for paradise & seek refuge from fire",
            "answer": "Narrated by Abu Huraira (RA): The Messenger of Allah (ﷺ), asked a man, What do you supplicate in your prayer? The man says, I recite Tashahhud and say- (The dua is mentioned above) I can’t recite dua as beautifully as you, nor can I recite dua like Muadh! Then Prophet (ﷺ) said, We also supplicate like you!",
            "reference": "Sahih (Albani). Ibn Majah: 910"
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "_id": "1d",
        "section": "Dua to remain steadfast on the religion",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "To get Stability in religion and good results in all deeds",
            "answer": "Abdullah bin Amr bin al-'As (RA) reported that he heard Allah's Messenger (ﷺ) as saying: Verily, the hearts of all the sons of Adam are between the two fingers out of the fingers of the Compassionate Lord as one heart. He turns that to any (direction) He likes. Then Allah’s Messenger (ﷺ) said: (Dua mentioned above)",
            "reference": "Muslim: 2655"
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "_id": "1e",
        "section": "Shelter from horror, misery, evil consequences and rejoicing of the enemy",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "Shelter from evil consequences and rejoicing of the enemy",
            "answer": "Translation: O Allah, I seek refuge in you from grief and sadness, from weakness and from laziness, from miserliness and from cowardice, from being overcome by debt and overpowered by men (i.e. others).",
            "reference": "Bukhari :2893"
          }
        ]
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "_id": "asdff",
    "cat": "Dua's Excellence",
    "subCat": [
      {
        "_id": "2a",
        "section": "Excellence of doing Tasbeeh, Tahmid, Tahlil, Takbeer",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "The reward of freeing the four slaves of Bani Ismail (AS)",
            "answer": "Translation: None has the right to be worshipped except Allah, alone, without any partner. To Him belong all sovereignty and praise and He is over all things omnipotent. Whoever says this dua ten times is like one who has freed four slaves from among the children of Ismaa'eel.",
            "reference": "Bukhari No: 6403; Muslim No: 2693"
          }
        ]
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "_id": "aDfdfadf",
    "cat": "Time of dua",
    "subCat": [
      {
        "_id": "3a",
        "section": "Times and places when dua will be accepted",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "Time when duas are accepted #1",
            "answer": "Narrated by Abdullah ibn Amr ibn al-'As (RA): A man said: O Messenger of Allah, the mu'adhdhins excel us. The Messenger of Allah (ﷺ) said: Say (the same words) as they say, and when you come to the end, ask Allah for anything and that will be granted to you.",
            "reference": "Hasan (Albani). Abu Dawud: 524"
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "_id": "3b",
        "section": "Time when duas are accepted",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "Time when duas are accepted #2",
            "answer": "Anas (RA) said, the Prophet (ﷺ) said, when the call to prayer (adhan) is given, the gates of heaven are opened and the dua is accepted.",
            "reference": "Sahih (Albani). Silsila Sahihah: 1413"
          }
        ]
      }
    ]
  }
]
